# **Matt Baker**

baker.matt.b@gmail.com

205.907.2978

9 1084 Springfield Dr. Chelsea, AL 35043

http://bakey.us/

## **Profile**

Currently fascinated with automation, infrastructure as code, containers, monitoring/metrics, visibility, and the culture of DevOps. I have nearly 15 years of stable, secure, and reliable systems administration across multiple technology stacks. Comfortable working alone but prefer working in a team environment, biased towards action, and prefer to learn by doing.

# **Technology**

Ansible, CloudFormation, GitLab, Jenkins, Bash, Python, PowerShell, Docker, Splunk, RHEL 6.x and 7.x, RHEV, Satellite 6, Citrix NetScaler load balancing, DHCP, DNS, AD, Hyper-V, VMWare, Nagios, Windows Server 2012 R2 and prior, Systems Center Operations Manager (SCOM), Systems Center Virtual Machine Manager (SCVMM), System Center Configuration Manager (SCCM), Windows Server Update Services (WSUS), Cisco wireless, routing, and switching platforms, Cisco ASA security platforms.

# **Employment**

**DevOps Engineer:** Kemper Insurance | Dec 2018 - Present

- Joined a brand-new team spearheading AWS adoption
- Quickly migrated several Ansible practices from on-premise procedures to meet AWS server configuration needs, enabling "one click" deployments of several different application stacks
- Working within an Agile framework, executing tasks in sprints and tracking several big projects to completion including:
  - New claims environment entirely configured in AWS in multiple accounts
  - New auto insurance environment entirely configured in AWS in multiple accounts
  - Successful code testing (linting) and git branching strategies to enable smoother workflows across our team
- Wrote singlehandedly or co-wrote multiple tools that allow easy CloudFormation stack creations and modifications to be executed from Jenkins
- Daily operate in a workflow that involves Git, Jenkins, Ansible, and CloudFormation

Unix Systems Administrator: Infinity Auto/Kemper Insurance | July 2015 - Dec 2018

 Spearheaded Ansible adoption on our team, successfully automating the following tasks:

- RHEL server builds executed from Jenkins with full tie-ins to Nagios, NetBackup, NetScaler load balancer, and Satellite 6.
- o RHEL server patching with MS Teams integration.
- o Middleware automation around Citrix NetScaler load balancer.
- o Dev self-service Nagios alert creation/deletion via Jenkins.
- Audit self-service /etc/passwd file retrieval for certain systems with full CI/CD including Jenkins and GitLab integration.
- Claims team self-service FTP file validation with full CI/CD including Jenkins and GitLab integration.
- Successfully driving infrastructure-as-code mentality on our team, including all Ansible playbooks being saved into GitLab.
- Led on the following projects:
  - Multiple Splunk architecture projects that resulted in a very robust clustered environment and drastic performance increases across the board.
  - Citrix NetScaler load balancer architecture, now spanning multiple HA pairs across environments.
  - o Satellite 5 to 6 migration including implementation of server patching
  - Container platform evaluations for OpenShift, Pivotal Cloud Foundry, and Docker Swarm
- Assisted in migrating our production datacenter into a new building.
- Assisted in migrating our dev/test environment into a new co-located facility.

#### Windows Systems Administrator II: Infinity Auto Insurance | Oct 2013 - July 2015

- Team as a whole was responsible daily for approximately 350 virtual and physical servers supporting 2000+ employees.
- Lead administrator on WSUS, SCCM, Hyper-V, and VMware View.
- Led team in the migration of a 200+ user VDI environment from VMWare View 5.0 to 6.0 with no downtime.
- Led team in researching, benchmarking, testing and implementing Hyper-V as a replacement virtualization platform for our Windows environment, including the implementation of a 6 node HA cluster and a custom PowerShell script to migrate VMs out of ESXi into Hyper-V.
- Installed, configured, and implemented test server WSUS/SCCM patch deployment for 70+ test and dev servers for Windows. Some of these servers had gone over a year without being patched.

#### Systems Administrator: Geographic Information Services, Inc. | 2009 - Oct 2013

- Solely responsible for all IT systems including VOIP, routing, switching, firewalls, desktops, and servers from 2009-2012.
- Brought all IT support back in-house saving thousands in consultant costs and dramatically reducing problem response time.
- Implemented network wide server monitoring with Nagios/MRTG/Spiceworks resulting in proactive server and systems maintenance that led to very low systems downtime during my tenure.
- Migrated a 2-node standalone VMware 3.5 environment to a 3-node VMware 4.0 cluster and implemented high availability with failover.
- Migrated from a single-name domain and forest to a new Active Directory Domain and Exchange server environment with no downtime.
- Implemented workstation standardization policy including hardware platforms and system images.
- Trained a second team member in 2012 who then went on to smoothly transition into my role when I left the company in 2013.

#### Systems Engineer: Diagnostic Health Corporation | 2008-2009

- Brought Cisco ASA support back in-house saving thousands in consultant costs and reducing turnaround time by days.
- Implemented new backup policies with Veritas NetBackup for terabytes worth of corporate data.
- Implemented change control processes to ensure proper IT implementation controls.
- Installed, configured, and maintained a 3 node VMware ESX 3.5 environment with iSCSI shared storage on an EMC Celerra.
- Completed an Active Directory migration and workstation re-imaging project.

### Network Engineer: Phoebe Putney Memorial Hospital | 2005-2008

- Assisted as part of a 5-man team with massive network infrastructure replacement. Replaced legacy Nortel L2 and L3 switches with Cisco 6500 series and 3000 series switches. Cut over 70+ LVCs and 4 core L3 switches in about 9 months.
- Led my team in an Active Directory in place upgrade from 2000 to 2003 across 5 domain controllers. Project completed with zero user downtime, ahead of schedule, and under budget.
- Installed, configured, and implemented complete SMS 2003 environment with WSUS updates on ~2000 workstations and servers. All workstations went from being totally unpatched to being fully patched up to the latest Microsoft updates within 6 weeks.
- Oversaw antivirus/anti-spam changeover from Symantec to Sophos on ~2000 workstations and servers with no downtime.
- Led in the installation of a Sophos mail filtering server that blocked hundreds of thousands of spam emails daily.

#### Network Technician: Select-Tel Systems, Inc. | 2004-2005

- Repaired, configured, upgraded, and secured desktop and server systems including hardware and software, entering most of these environments blindly and having to assess and problem solve each task.
- Setup and configured new PCs, HP servers, Cisco routers, switches, and firewalls.
- Made recommendations to customers regarding purchase of computer equipment and software.

#### **Education**

## Bachelor of Applied Science in Information Technology: Valdosta State University

- Graduated in 2002
- Dean's List multiple semesters